Guide to the Elizabeth Bishop Papers, circa 1880-2023 (bulk 1929-1979)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Elizabeth Bishop Papers
circa 1880-2023
1929-1979
Bishop, Elizabeth, 1911-1979
42.6 cubic feet (125 boxes, 22 boxes of photocopies and reproductions)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Correspondence, diaries, notebooks, manuscripts and drafts, memorabilia, artwork, publications, and photographs relating to Bishop's personal and professional life. Also, letters, minutes, contracts, and financial records from her teaching and publishing activities, 1943-1979; manuscripts, typescripts, drafts, revisions, and fragments of her poetry and prose writings, 1929-1979; Vassar student notebooks, travel diaries, notes from her 17-year residence in Brazil, and family information, 1931-1977; manuscripts, typescripts, articles, essays, and poetry by or about other writers, especially Robert Lowell, 1925-1979; and printed poetry, prose, reviews, and articles by or about Bishop.
Biographical Note
Elizabeth Bishop (8 February 1911 - 6 October 1979) was a Pulitzer-Prize winning poet, Consultant in Poetry to the Library of Congress, and winner of the National Book Award. She was born in Worcester, Massachusetts in 1911 but after her father's death and mother's hospitalization was raised by other relatives, and her fondest childhood memories were of Nova Scotia and Cape Cod. In 1934 Bishop graduated from Vassar College. In addition to working on the school newspaper, The Vassar Miscellany, Bishop founded a literary magazine, Con Spirito, with fellow students Mary McCarthy, Eleanor Clark, and Muriel Rukeyser. Following graduation, Bishop spent several years traveling. She stayed in New York, as well as various cities in Europe and North Africa, but she finally found a home in Key West, Florida, where she made several influential friends and found inspiration for many of her most significant poems. When World War II turned Key West into a military command center, Bishop packed her suitcase again. After brief periods in Washington, an artists' colony in upstate New York and a return to New York City, Bishop set out on what was supposed to be a voyage around the world by ship. But in Rio de Janeiro, the first port, she had an allergic reaction to the fruit of a cashew and was nursed back to health by Maria Carlota de Macedo Soares. She and "Lota" fell in love and Bishop made Brazil her home for the next 17 years. She returned to the States only when in the mid 1960s it became financially necessary. She accepted teaching positions at the University of Washington, then Harvard, followed seven years later by New York University, and just prior to her death, the Massachusetts Institute of Technology.
Scope and Content Note
The Elizabeth Bishop Papers consist of correspondence, personal papers, working papers, notebooks, diaries, and memorabilia as well as a substantial amount of material by and about her friends and colleagues. Among the collection are over 3,500 pages of drafts of poems and prose, over 200 letters from Marianne Moore written between 1935 and 1969 discussing their work and mutual friends; and over 200 letters from Robert Lowell written between 1947 and 1976 discussing his work and that of Bishop's and her influence on his work, as well as the work of other writers including Ezra Pound, William Carlos Williams, W.H. Auden, Sylvia Plath, Flannery O'Connor, and Mary McCarthy.
Other correspondents include: Leonie Adams, John Ashbery, John Berryman, Harold Bloom, Robert Bly, Louise Bogan, John Malcolm Brinnin, Seamus Heaney, Anthony Hecht, Randall Jarrell, Archibald MacLeish, James Merrill, Henry Moore, Howard Moss, Octavio Paz, Katherine Anne Porter, Muriel Rukeyser, Anne Sexton, Mark Strand, May Swenson, Allen Tate, Dylan Thomas, Alice B. Toklas, John Updike, Eudora Welty, and Edmund Wilson.
The collection also contains letters from Elizabeth Bishop to James Merrill, Pearl Kazin Bell, Loren MacIver and Lloyd Frankenberg, Anny Baumann, and other friends and relatives. Of particular note are letters to and from Maria Carlota "Lota" de Macedo Soares.
The Elizabeth Bishop Papers also include the only extant typescript of her 1939 poem, "Pleasure Seas," photographs, slides, watercolors by Elizabeth Bishop, diplomas, academic hoods, citations, and her Brazilian oil lamp.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
. However, researchers will generally be required to use photocopies and not original material due to frequent research requests and the collection's fragility.
Related Materials
Translations, transcriptions, and annotations: Translations by Lilli Correia de Araújo of eight letters written in Portuguese by Lota de Macedo Soares to Bishop in 1964 are available. Also available are transcriptions and annotations by David Hoak of: 1) correspondence from Lota to Bishop in 1967, and 2) letters from Bishop to Ruth Foster.
Elizabeth Bishop Estate and Posthumous Events Collection
Iannucci Modern American Literature Manuscript Collection
Margaret Miller Papers
Esther Merrell Stockton Papers
Vassar College Alumnae/i Authors Files — Elizabeth Bishop Files
Photocopies of Bishop's letters to Marianne Moore are on deposit at Vassar from the Marianne Moore Papers at the Rosenbach Library and Museum, Philadelphia, PA.
Separated Materials
Separated Material: 5 boxes of galleys and other material related to work published after Bishop's death were moved to the Elizabeth Bishop Estate and Posthumous Events Collection in 2012. This does not include Bishop's original drafts, but rather the work done by Alice and Bishop's editors after Bishop's death. The boxes included were 50-51 (The Collected Prose) and 61-63 (The Complete Poems). One additional typescript was also moved: "A Trip to Vigia."
Separated Material: Some material relating to celebrations of Bishop and her work were moved to the Elizabeth Bishop Estate and Posthumous Events Collection in April 2012.
Separated Material: The card index to Bishop's library was removed from Box 111 and placed in the card catalog in the Archives and Special Collections office.
Subject Headings
Names:
Moore, Marianne, 1887-1972; Lowell, Robert, 1917-1977; Soares, Lota de Macedo, 1910-1967; McCarthy, Mary, 1912-1989; Clark, Eleanor, 1913-1996; Rukeyser, Muriel, 1913-1980; Adams, Léonie, 1899-; Ashbery, John, 1927-2017; Berryman, John, 1914-1972; Bloom, Harold; Bly, Robert; Bogan, Louise, 1897-1970; Brinnin, John Malcolm, 1916-; Calder, Alexander, 1898-1976; Cummings, E. E. (Edward Estlin), 1894-1962; Fitzgerald, Robert, 1910-; Hardwick, Elizabeth; Heaney, Seamus; Hecht, Anthony, 1923-; Jarrell, Randall, 1914-1965; MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-1982; Merrill, James Ingram; Moore, Henry, 1898-; Paz, Octavio, 1914-; Porter, Katherine Anne, 1894-; Sexton, Anne; Swenson, May; Tate, Allen, 1899-; Thomas, Dylan, 1914-1953; Toklas, Alice B.; Bell, Pearl K.; Baumann, Anny; Bishop family
Organizations:
Vassar College--Students; Library of Congress
Subjects:
Women--Diaries; Literature--Authors; Literature--Study and teaching; Poets; Women poets; Women teachers
Places:
Brazil--Description and travel
Document Types:
Autographs; Correspondence; Diaries; Drawings (visual works); Notebooks; Paintings (visual works); Photographs; Printed materials (object genre); Poems; Realia; Signatures (names)
VCL Categories:
Latin America; LGBTQ (Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender and Queer) Life and Culture; Literature and Writing
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke, February 2007. Last updated by Emma Gronbeck, May 2025.
Acquisition Information
Purchase Sources Include: Alice H. Methfessel, Anny Baumann, Phyllis Sutherland, Linda Nemer, E. Wharton and Co., Glenn Horowitz, Bookseller; Katharine O. Sargent, Emanuel Brasil, Estella Pereira, Richard Levey, Irvine Huck, Philip Booth, H. E. Turlington Books, Lilli Correia de Araújo, James S. Jaffe Rare Books, the Portinari Family, and Gesoki Booksellers.
Gift Sources Include: An anonymous donor, James Merrill, Alice H. Methfessel, Pearl K. Bell, Howard Moss, Rollie McKenna, U.T. and Joseph Summers, Frani Blough Muser, the Margaret Bradley Sherman Library Fund (of Vassar College), Helen Muchnic, James Laughlin, Estate of Victor L. O. Chittick, Harriet Thomas Tompkins.
Additions to the collection since 2000 are located in boxes 112-128.
Location of Originals
Researchers may read photocopies of the Elizabeth Bishop letters to Marianne Moore from the Marianne Moore Papers that are on deposit here at Vassar courtesy of the Rosenbach Library and Museum. All permissions relating to this collection should be directed to the Rosenbach.
James Laughlin donated photocopies of the correspondence he received from Bishop; the original letters remain in his possession.
Series List
- Series I. CORRESPONDENCE, 1911-1983
  - Letters to Elizabeth Bishop, 1934-1979
  - Letters from Elizabeth Bishop, 1928-1979
  - Letters between Others, 1911-1983
- Series II. PROFESSIONAL CORRESPONDENCE, CONTRACTS, AND FINANCIAL STATEMENTS, 1943-2003
- Series III. PERSONAL FINANCIAL AND LEGAL DOCUMENTS, 1932-1979
- Series IV. BISHOP'S PROSE, 1933-1977
  Listed chronologically by date of publication, or if no date is available, alphabetically by title. Note: Dates in brackets indicate the date of publication not the date of creation
  - Published Prose, 1937-1977
  - Unpublished Prose, 1933-1970, undated
- Series V. BISHOP'S POETRY, [circa 1928?]-1979
  - Published Poetry, 1929-1978
  - Unpublished Poetry, [circa 1928?]-1979
- Series VI. FRAGMENTS (PROSE AND POETRY), undated
- Series VII. NOTES AND NOTEBOOKS, 1928-1977
- Series VIII. TRAVEL JOURNALS AND NOTES, 1932-1979
- Series IX. DATEBOOKS AND CALENDARS, 1950-1978
- Series X. BIOGRAPHICAL AND FAMILY DATA, 1903-1979
- Series XI. WORKS BY OTHERS, 1941-1979
- Series XII. PRINTED MATERIAL, 1926-1979
- Series XIII. PHOTOGRAPHS, circa 1908 - circa 1995
- Series XIV. ARTWORK, 1937-1979, undated
- Series XV. MEMORABILIA AND EPHEMERA, circa 1880 - 1975
- Series XVI. PHOTOCOPIES AND REPRODUCTIONS, 2023, undated
  This series consists of photocopies and other reproductions of materials from the first fifteen series in this collection, as well as copies of letters from the Marianne Moore Papers at the Rosenbach Museum and Library. The majority of these photocopies were made at some point during the late 20th century in order to provide access to the papers while minimizing wear and tear to the originals. Enlarged photographic reproductions of Bishop's slides of Brazil are also included.
Container List
- SERIES I. CORRESPONDENCE
  - Letters to Elizabeth Bishop
    - Adams, Leonie, 1949-1977; (4 letters) (Folder 1.1)
    - Alfred, William, 1970-1971; (2 letters) (Folder 1.2)
    - Aldrich, Priscilla [Coe?], 1977 Dec; (1 letter) (Folder 115.20)
    - Almyda, Hanna, 1961-1963; (2 letters) (Folder 1.3)
    - Andrade, Rodrigo Melo Franco, 1961; (1 letter) (Folder 1.4)
    - Andrade, Carlos Drummond de (1902-1987), 1963-1969; (3 letters) (Folder 1.5)
    - Ashbery, John, 1976; (2 letters and 1 Christmas card) (Folder 1.6)
    - Ballard, Elizabeth, 1976; (1 letter with music manuscript, 1 postcard) (Folder 1.7)
    - Bandeira, M., 1953; (3 letters) (Folder 1.8)
    - Barker, Ilse and Kit, 1968-1979; (19 letters with 2 photos) (Folder 1.9)
    - Baro, Gene, 1964 Aug 11; (1 postcard) (Folder 22.4)
    - Baumann, Anny, 1948-1954; (5 letters) (Folder 1.10)
    - Baumann, Anny, 1964, 1979; (2 letters) (Folder 115.22)
    - Baumann, Anny, 1978-1979, undated; (8 letters) (Folder 1.11)
    - Benton, Betty, 1974-1978; (5 letters, 1cc from E. Bishop) (Folder 1.12)
    - [Bernard], April, [1979]; (1 letter) (Folder 22.5)
    - Berresford, Virginia, 1977 Dec; (1 letter) (Folder 22.6)
    - Berryman, John, 1969-1970; (2 letters) (Folder 1.13)
    - Bidart, Frank, 1971-1972; (9 letters) (Folder 1.14)
    - Biddle, Katherine, undated; (2 letters, 1 greeting card) (Folder 1.15)
    - Blackburn, Roma, 1978-1979; (13 letters) (Folder 1.16)
    - Bloom, Harold, 1977; (l letter) (Folder 2.1)
    - Bloom, Hyman, 1947-1958; (2 letters) (Folder 2.2)
    - Bly, Robert, 1969; (2 letters) (Folder 2.3)
    - Bogan, Louise, 1955; (1 postcard) (Folder 2.4)
    - Booth, Philip, 1973-1979; (6 letters) (Folder 2.5)
    - [Bowers], Aunt Grace, undated; (1 letter) (Folder 22.7)
    - Bowie, Dorothee M., 1970 Jun; (4 letters) [RESTRICTED] (Folder 115.23)
    - Bowie, Dorothee M., 1971-1979; (4 letters) (Folder 2.6)
    - Bowie, Dorothee, 1974 Oct 13, 20; (2 postcards) (Folder 121.11)
    - Bowie, Dorothee M., 1978-1979; (3 letters, 1 booklet, 1 business card) (Folder 115.24)
    - Boxer, C. R., 1970; (1 letter) (Folder 2.7)
    - Bradt, George and Hilary (re: Casa Mariana), [1974]; (7 letters. 1 news clipping) (Folder 115.25)
    - Brasil, Emanuel, 1969 Mar 18; (1 letter) (Folder 114.11)
    - Brasil, Emanuel, [1969?]-1977; (4 letters, 3 enclosures) (Folder 115.26)
    - Brinnan, John Malcolm, 1954-1978; (7 letters) (Folder 2.8)
    - Brinnan, John Malcolm, 1978-1979; (8 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 2.9)
    - Brown, Ashley, 1968-1979; (6 letters, 1 postcard, 1 Christmas card) (Folder 2.10)
    - Budenz, Julia, 1972-1979; (5 letters) (Folder 2.11)
    - Budenz, Julia, 1973 Aug 7; (2 letters) (Folder 115.27)
    - Bulmer, [Aunt] Mabel, 1959; (2 letters) (Folder 22.8)
    - Calder, Alexander, 1960-1962, undated; (3 letters, 1 note with drawing) (Folder 2.12)
    - Calder, Louisa, 1967 Nov 15; (1 letter) (Folder 115.28)
    - Carlile, Sandra McPherson and Henry, 1974-1979; (6 letters) (Folder 2.13)
    - Carter, Elliott, 1975; (1 letter) (Folder 2.14)
    - Chittick, V. L. O. and Edna, 1954-1969, undated; (8 letters with 1 letter from Lois, 1 Christmas card) (Folder 2.15)
    - Corn, Alfred, 1978; (1 letter) (Folder 2.16)
    - Correia de Araújo, Lilli, 1967-1968; (4 letters) (Folder 114.10)
    - Correia de Araújo, Lilli, 1967 Sep 30; (1 telegram) (Folder 115.21)
    - Crane, Louise, 1968-1973, undated; (5 letters, 1 note) (Folder 3.1)
    - Cummings, e. e., 1953-1958; (1 letter with 2 enclosures, 3 postcards) (Folder 3.2)
    - De Jesus, Vitoria, 1973; (1 letter) (Folder 3.3)
    - De Jesus, Vitoria, 1974; (8 letters, 3 receipts) (Folder 115.29)
    - Deutsch, Babette, 1962; (1 letter) (Folder 3.4)
    - Dewey, Evelyn, 1952-1954; (2 letters) (Folder 3.5)
    - Dewey, Jane, 1959-1968; (5 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 3.6)
    - Dewey, John, 1945-1946; (2 letters) (Folder 3.7)
    - Donoghue, Denis, 1962; (1 letter) (Folder 3.8)
    - Dunford-Wood, Hugh, 1977; (4 letters) (Folder 115.30)
    - Dunford-Wood, Hugh, 1977-1978; (4 letters) (Folder 3.9)
    - Eberhart, Richard, 1968-1979; (1 letter, 1 postcard) (Folder 3.10)
    - Ehrenpreis, Irvin, 1971-1979; (7 letters) (Folder 3.11)
    - Elliott, George P., 1955-1956; (4 letters) (Folder 3.12)
    - Engelberg, Ed, 1978; (2 letters) (Folder 3.13)
    - Estess, Sybil, 1974-1979; (7 letters) (Folder 3.14)
    - Ettinger, Maia, 1978-1979; (1 letter, 1 postcard, 1 Christmas card) (Folder 3.15)
    - Feo, José Rodriguez, 1944-1945; (3 letters) (Folder 3.16)
    - Ferry, David, 1976-1978; (2 letters) (Folder 3.17)
    - Fisher, Anna Helena, 1978; (1 letter) (Folder 3.18)
    - Fitzgerald, Robert, 1971-1977, undated; (3 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 3.19)
    - Fitzgerald, Sally, 1979; (1 letter) (Folder 3.20)
    - Fizdale, Robert, 1958-1969; (8 letters, 2 postcards) (Folder 4.1)
    - Fizdale, Robert, 1970-1977, undated; (9 letters, 1 postcard, 1 Christmas card) (Folder 4.2)
    - Fizdale, Robert and Arthur Gold, [no year] Feb 14; (1 postcard) (Folder 121.11)
    - Frank, Joe, 1950-1964; (6 letters) (Folder 4.3)
    - Frankenberg, Lloyd, 1941-1961; (8 letters) (Folder 4.4)
    - Frederica, Antoinette, 1978; (2 letters) (Folder 4.5)
    - Frye, Northrop, 1975; (1 letter) (Folder 4.6)
    - Galassi, Jonathan, 1971-1979; (7 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 4.7)
    - Gardner, Isabella, 1955-1961, undated; (4 letters) (Folder 4.8)
    - Godfrey, Judy and Roger (re: Casa Mariana), 1974 Sep 4; (1 letter) (Folder 115.31)
    - Grigg, C., approximately 1974-1975; (1 postcard) (Folder 121.11)
    - Gunn, Thom, 1968-1970; (1 letter, 1 postcard) (Folder 4.9)
    - Halpern, Daniel, 1979, undated; (1 letter, 1 postcard) (Folder 4.10)
    - Hardwick, Elizabeth, 1950-1963; (8 letters, 2 telegrams, with 1 letter from E. Bishop) (Folder 4.11)
    - Hardwick, Elizabeth, 1964-1978; (7 letters) (Folder 4.12)
    - Harper, Michael, 1973; (1 letter) (Folder 4.13)
    - Harris, Julie, 1976 Apr 2; (1 postcard) (Folder 115.32)
    - Heaney, Seamus, 1979; (1 letter, 1 postcard) (Folder 5.1)
    - Hecht, Anthony, 1969-1979; (5 letters) (Folder 5.2)
    - Hershey, Judith, 1976-1977; (2 letters, 2 postcards) (Folder 5.3)
    - Hoffman, "Liz" and Daniel, 1974 Sep 16; (1 postcard) (Folder 121.11)
    - Holland, Henrietta, 1953-1956; (2 letters) (Folder 5.4)
    - Hollander, John, 1977; (1 letter) (Folder 5.5)
    - Howard, Richard, 1974 Sep-Oct; (2 postcards) (Folder 121.11)
    - Howes, Barbara, 1977 Dec; (1 Christmas card) (Folder 22.9)
    - Hoyt, Chris, 1974-1978, undated; (19 letters, 4 postcards) (Folder 116.1)
    - Hull, Donald, 1961; (1 letter) (Folder 5.6)
    - Hussey, Anne, 1971-1979, undated; (9 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 5.7)
    - Janowitz, Phyllis, 1979 Mar 6; (1 letter) (Folder 22.10)
    - Jarrell, Mackie (Mrs. Randall), 1952; (1 letter) (Folder 5.10)
    - Jarrell, Randall, 1949-1956; (4 letters) (Folder 5.8)
    - Jarrell, Randall, 1957-1964; (3 letters) (Folder 5.9)
    - Jefferson, Margo, 1979 Feb 17; (1 letter) (Folder 22.11)
    - Johnson, Judy (Walnut Hill School friend), 1969 May 7; (1 letter) (Folder 116.2)
    - Kalstone, David, 1969, undated; (2 letters) (Folder 5.12)
    - Kalstone, David, 1971 Nov 12; (1 ALS) (Folder 127.13)
      Note: Removed from Bishop's copy of Alfred Kazin's Contemporaries,
      Grille PS 3521 A995 C6
      .
    - Kaplan, Peter, 1973; (2 letters) (Folder 5.13)
    - Keller, Roberta Lynn, 1979; (2 letters, 1 cc from E. Bishop) (Folder 5.14)
    - Kentfield, Calvin, 1951-1952, undated; (4 letters) (Folder 5.15)
    - Kessler, Milton, 1971 Jan 4; (1 postcard) (Folder 121.11)
    - Krupat, Arnold and Cynthia, 1969 Jan; (2 letters) (Folder 22.12)
    - Lacerda, Carlos, 1952; (1 letter) (Folder 6.1)
    - Lafeuille, Germaine, 1964-1973; (7 letters, 2 cc from E. Bishop, 3 letters to Lafeuille, 2 cc from Lafeuille to Claude Roy, 1 cc from Lafeuille to R. Gallimard) (Folder 6.2)
    - Larkin, Philip, 1964; (1 letter) (Folder 6.3)
    - Lattimore, David (son of Owen Lattimore), 1976 Apr 9; (2 letters) (Folder 116.3)
    - Laurans, Penelope, 1979; (1 letter) (Folder 6.4)
    - Leão, Rosalina Azevedo and Magú Costa Ribeiro, 1967 Sep 27; (1 telegram) (Folder 22.13)
    - Leão, Rosalina Azevedo and Magú Costa Ribeiro, [1967] Sep 28; (1 letter) (Folder 114.12)
    - Leão, Rosalina Azevedo, 1967 Oct 11; (1 letter) (Folder 116.4)
    - Ledford-Miller, Linda, 1978-1979; (9 letters, 4 cc from E. Bishop) (Folder 6.5)
    - [Leeds, Harold ?], [approximately 1968 Jan]; (1 postcard) (Folder 114.13)
    - Leh, William, 1974-1975; (2 letters) (Folder 6. 6)
    - Leithauser, Brad, 1978; (2 letters) (Folder 6.7)
    - Lerman, Leo, 1948 Apr 20; (1 letter fragment) (Folder 22.14)
    - Levering, Frank, 1978; (1 letter) (Folder 6.8)
    - Levitin, Alexis, 1975 Sep 21; (1 letter, 1 bibliography) (Folder 116.5)
    - Littlefield, Lester, 1942-1968; (10 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 6.9)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1947; (7 letters, 1 postcard, cc of Falling Asleep Over the Aeneid) (Folder 7.1)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1948 Jan-Jul; (11 letters) (Folder 7.2)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1948 Aug-Dec; (10 letters, 2 postcards) (Folder 7.3)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1949; (7 letters) (Folder 7.4)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1950; (6 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 7.5)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1951; (3 letters) (Folder 7.6)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1952; (2 letters) (Folder 7.7)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1953; (3 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 7.8)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1954; (2 letters) (Folder 7.9)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1955; (4 letters) (Folder 7.10)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1956; (4 letters) (Folder 7.11)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1957 Feb-Jul; (7 letters) (Folder 8.1)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1957 Aug-Dec; (7 letters, 1 telegram) (Folder 8.2)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1958; (7 letters) (Folder 8.3)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1959; (8 letters) (Folder 8.4)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1960; (10 letters, 1 telegram) (Folder 8.5)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1961; (6 letters) (Folder 8.6)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1962; (8 letters) (Folder 8.7)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1963; (9 letters) (Folder 8.8)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1964; (11 letters) (Folder 9.1)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1965-1966; (10 letters) (Folder 9.2)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1967-1968; (10 letters) (Folder 9.3)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1969-1970; (10 letters) (Folder 9.4)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1971-1972; (13 letters) (Folder 9.5)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1972 Jul 8; (1 letter - originally enclosed with 17 July 1972 letter from Elizabeth Bishop to Alice Methfessel) (Folder 114.14)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1973-1976; (24 letters, 1 telegram) (Folder 9.6)
    - Lowell, Robert, various; (12 postcards) (Folder 9.7)
    - Lushington, Beatrice [O'Connel Roethke, 1977 Dec 4; (1 Christmas card) (Folder 22.15)
    - Machado, Alfredo C., 1969; (1 letter) (Folder 22.16)
    - MacLeish, Archibald, 1953-1972 undated; (3 letters) (Folder 10.2)
      MacLeish, Archibald — See also Lowell
    - McCarthy, Mary, 1979; (2 letters) (Folder 10.3)
    - McKenna, Rollie, 1968; (1 letter) (Folder 10.4)
    - [MacIver, Loren and Lloyd Frankenberg?], 1968 Mar 9; (1 postcard) (Folder 116.6)
    - MacMahon, Candace, 1977 Dec 9; (1 letter on the back of bibliography) (Folder 116.7)
    - MacMahon, Candace, 1977-1979; (13 letters) (Folder 10.5)
    - McMahon, Eileen, 1978; (1 letter) (Folder 10.6)
    - Manrique, Jaime, 1978; (4 letters) (Folder 10.7)
    - Martin, James [Boston University], 1971 Mar; (1 letter) (Folder 22.17)
    - Mazzaro, Jerome, 1978; (1 letter) (Folder 10.8)
    - Mazzocco, Robert, 1972; (1 letter) (Folder 10.9)
    - Meigs, Mary, 1977 Dec; (1 Christmas card) (Folder 22.18)
    - Melo Neto, Joao Cabral de, 1956-1966; (3 letters) (Folder 10.10)
    - Menzes, Antonio Cicero de, 1956; (1 letter) (Folder 10.11)
    - Merrill, Charles Jr., 1977 Dec; (1 Christmas card) (Folder 22.19)
    - Merrill, James, 1959-1970; (14 letters, 2 postcards) (Folder 11.1)
    - Merrill, James, 1971 Jun 6; (1 letter - torn into 3 pieces) (Folder 114.15)
    - Merrill, James, 1971-1979; (20 letters, 12 postcards, 1 fragment) (Folder 11.2)
    - Methfessel, Alice, 1970; (2 letters) (Folder 116.8)
    - Methfessel, Alice, 1971 Feb 1-9; (4 letters, 1 greeting card) (Folder 116.9)
    - Methfessel, Alice, 1971 Feb 11-15; (2 letters, 1 news clipping) (Folder 116.10)
    - Methfessel, Alice, 1971 Feb 16-20; (5 letters, 1 greeting card) (Folder 116.11)
    - Methfessel, Alice, 1971 Feb 21-[28]; (5 letters) (Folder 116.12)
    - Methfessel, Alice, 1971 Mar 2-7; (6 letters) (Folder 116.13)
    - Methfessel, Alice, 1971 Mar 8-21; (6 letters, 1 greeting card) (Folder 116.14)
    - Methfessel, Alice, 1971 Mar 22-31; (6 letters) (Folder 116.15)
    - Methfessel, Alice, 1971 Apr 1-14; (7 letters) (Folder 116.16)
    - Methfessel, Alice, 1971 Apr 15-20; (1 postcard, 6 letters - 1 photocopied) (Folder 116.17)
    - Methfessel, Alice, 1971 Apr 21-29; (6 letters) (Folder 116.18)
    - Methfessel, Alice, 1971 May; (7 letters) (Folder 116.19)
    - Methfessel, Alice, 1971 Jul 2-11; (8 letters) (Folder 116.20)
    - Methfessel, Alice, 1971 Jul 12-17; (7 letters) (Folder 116.21)
    - Methfessel, Alice, 1971 Jul 18-28; (6 letters, 1 carbon, 2 postcards) (Folder 116.22)